If you want to know more about my professional experience and education, you can check this extensive resume about Audiovisual Translation, as well as project managing, close captioning and teaching. I work from English to Spanish.

Ángeles Vazquez Freelance translator English-Spanish

Professional experience

- 2016-Present: Freelance translator
 - Subtitle translation, timing and QC
 - Subtitles for the Deaf or Hard of Hearing (Spanish)
 - Translation, QC and sync (takes) of scripts for voice-over dubbing
 - Translation and QC for scrips for lip-sync dubbing
- 11/2017, 11/2018: Captioning of live subtitles (Subtitula'm, Seville European Film Festival)
- 03/2018–06/2018: Proyect manager (P4 Traducciones)
- 09/2015–11/2016: Search Engine Evaluator (Leapforce)

•

Teaching

- 06/2019: Audiovisual Translation course, En pocas palabras: curso internacional de traducción y subtitulación (Olavide en Carmona, Universidad Pablo de Olavide)
 - "Aplicaciones de la traducción audiovisual" (Aplications of Audiovisual Translation)
 - o "Práctica de un encargo de subtitulación" (*A subtitling project workshop*)
 - "Empleabilidad y aspectos profesionales de la traducción audiovisual" (Employability and professional aspects of Audiovisual Translation)
- 06/2019: Round table discussion on freelancing and carreer guidance (Instituto Superior de Estudios Lingüísticos y Traducción)
- 04/2019: Meet-and-greet with students, Encuentra: Diálogo entre profesionales, estudiantes y egresados (Universidad Pablo de Olavide)
- 01/2018–11/2018: Audiovisual Translation Training: Teacher and internship tutor (P4 Traducciones)
- 07/2018: **Audiovisual Translation course**, En pocas palabras: curso internacional de traducción y subtitulación
 - (Olavide en Carmona, Universidad Pablo de Olavide)
 - o "La traducción de cine independiente" (Translation of independent cinema)
 - "Aplicaciones de la traducción audiovisual" (Aplications of Audiovisual Translation)

- "Empleabilidad y aspectos profesionales de la traducción audiovisual"
 (Employability and professional aspects of Audiovisual Translation)
- 06/2018: Conference, "¿Cómo hacerse un hueco en el marcado laboral de la traducción audiovisual?" (How to find work in Audiovisual Translation?) (Instituto Superior de Estudios Lingüísticos y Traducción)
- 05/2018: Meet-and-greet with students, Encuentra: Diálogo entre profesionales, estudiantes y egresados (Universidad Pablo de Olavide)

Internship and unpaid qualifications

- 2018: CITA: V Conferencia Internacional de Traducción Audiovisual, (5th International Audiovisual Translation Conference) organization (ATRAE, Asociación de Traducción y Adaptación Audiovisual de España, Universidad Pontificia de Comillas)
- 07/2016–10/2016: Internship in Audiovisual Translation (P4 Traducciones)
- 03/2016: Internship in Audiovisual Translation (Más Traducciones)
- 12/2009–01/2015: Vice-president, content manager and editor, proof-reader, webmaster (*H de Humanidades*, online Humanities magazine)
- 02/2014–07/2014: Internship in Editing (La Piedra Lunar, S.L.)
- 2013: Volunteer locator (TED Open Translation Project)

Education

- 2015–2016: Master's Degree in **Audiovisual Translation**: Localisation, Subtitling and Dubbing (Instituto Superior de Estudios Lingüísticos y Traducción)
- 2009–2014: Degree in **Translation and Interpreting** (Universidad Pablo de Olavide)
- 2009–2014: Degree in **Humanities** (Universidad Pablo de Olavide)

Non-related training

- 2015: Course in Advanced Word 2013 (Albali Centros de Formación)
- 2015: Course in Editing, Manual del Editor la moderna industria editorial (Albali Centros de Formación)
- 2015: InDesign CS6 course (Albali Centros de Formación)
- 2015: Course in Photoshop CS6 (Albali Centros de Formación)
- 11/2014–12/2014: Course in Editing, Experimental Press: Taller práctico de creación editorial (La Piedra Lunar, S. L., Centro de Iniciativas Culturales de la Universidad de Sevilla)